Good Morning, people of God!
Greet your neighbour, "Good Morning!"
Say, "Neighbour, Good Morning!"
Greet the viewers, say, "Viewers, Good Morning!"
Indeed, Good Morning to your life today!
Good Morning to your career!
Good Morning to your life!
Good Morning to your destiny!
It is a new dawn!
Do you believe that? Say, "Thank You, Jesus". Give thanks to Him.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Hallelujah!
Have your seat in His presence.
That joy shall be permanent.
It shall be permanent.
Please, forget the trouble that brought you here; it is no more a trouble.
Forget that problem that brought you here; it is no longer a problem because Jesus is alive.
Jesus is alive!
Thank You, Jesus, for the grace to be here today.
My name is Racine.
I am an evangelist here by the grace of God under my father in the Lord, Prophet T.B. Joshua.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
As you see me, God has done a miracle in my life.
If you saw me where I was before,
you would never believe that such a man could stand in your presence today.
God has visited my life through Prophet T.B. Joshua
and today, the same God will touch your life.
I want you to have the assurance I have today.
You may be having trouble deep inside your heart.
Trouble must have brought you here, but let me tell you,
there is Someone somewhere who is aware of your situation.
No matter how long you have been in darkness, the light shines.
The Scripture says, the prophetic light is the light shining in the darkness.
When you come out of darkness, you remain faithful to the light forever - Jesus is the light.
Thank You, Jesus, for my life.
Brethren, I want to just tell you a very short story about me.
Like many African people here,
we believe that the greener pastures are when we go to the western world - that, I did.
I lived there for twenty-two years - worked with people, met different people.
I thought I had 'arrived' - on the outside.
But one day, after eighteen years, something happened.
Something happened that turned my life around.
All that I counted dear, important, collapsed in one day.
That business I was proud of collapsed.
That relationship I was into for so long collapsed in one day - on the eve of Christmas, 1998.
I found myself stranded in a foreign country where I knew nobody.
I found myself on the streets, stranded - nowhere to go. I did not know anybody.
I had my bag and the phone I had switched off.
I was roaming about with nowhere to go, on a Christmas day.
That day my whole life said: "Is this what you have come to do in this country?
What are you going to do? What is the way out?"
Imagine what can go through the heart of such a person
Happening on the day of Christmas - everybody in his home fellowshipping, dancing and dining.
I was looking for a hotel and I could not find any.
I entered one hotel one day.
I was overwhelmed.
I entered that room tired, and I slept.
And I had a dream.
I dreamt - I saw a mountain, a very high mountain and I was like a baby
– eight months old baby wearing diapers.
I looked at the mountain - so high.
When I turned, I saw a man, as tall as the mountain - a black man, having a beard.
I looked at the mountain; I looked at the man. I said, "How can I go there?"
I looked at the man; the man looked at me and smiled.
I woke up.
When I woke up, something strange happened to me.
There was a small light, as if you lit a candle
At that moment, I said, "Who is this man?"
My focus changed immediately. I forgot about my trouble.
I said, "Who is this man?"
I looked for that man - from town to town.
I travelled to different countries to look for that man.
Anytime I heard, "There is man of God here", I ran there.
After four years, my life had not changed - the trouble was still there.
One day, I said, "God, if that dream is true, I will not allow water or food to enter my mouth
until you reveal to me that person".
For good six to seven days, I was there. And something happened.
Let somebody say, "Something happened".
On Monday, a friend called me and said, "Let's go to the prayer meeting
because they are going to show something very special and very strange".
So I went there.
What I saw shocked me.
The man I saw in the dream - they were calling that man, "The Man In The Synagogue".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
When they played that video, I saw a man sitting on the ground -
the buttocks were eaten by worms.
The man was abandoned; I was shocked to see the image.
I said, "How can this person live?"
Immediately, he came and prayed for that man.
When I saw the video, the man was healed, delivered - as if he was never sick.
I said, "This is the man".
The SCOAN Sunday Live Service
I began to say God: "How can I go there, how can I see him?"
I slept and another dream came, showing me the map of Africa.
Nigeria was like a heartbeat.
When I got to my office the next day, I told my boss, "I want to go to Nigeria".
He looked at me and said, "What happened to you? Are you crazy?"
I said, "No. There is a prophet there; I want to go and see him".
Before I realised it, he came to me, took a cheque book,
signed a cheque and got my ticket.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
So, I came here on February 2002.
On that fateful Sunday Service, the prophet saw me in his office.
When I entered, I couldn't talk. He gave me this.
This paper you see, has now been with me for good 16 years.
He looked at me and said, "What are you doing? God has a plan for you".
My dear brother,
if you don't know where you are destined to be, your destiny will be changed forever.
He gave me this; I took it and I read.
It says, "God will give you all that He has for His heirs".
That day, I understood that I am a child of promise.
So I wrote on the back: Sunday, 3 March 2002.
Immediately I read, something crossed my mind and said,
"If you believe in God, you will succeed. If you believe His prophet, you will prosper".
So, I went to the Scriptures and wrote down 2 Chronicles 20:20.
Today, my dream has come to pass.
What I want to tell you:
We are living in a world full of trouble but that trouble you are in today,
God may use it to release you to your future.
I'm telling you this to let you know that:
If you are in a situation, if what you are feeling in your heart is contrary to your heart's desire,
pause, take the time to change your focus, right now.
Stop thinking about your problem and start engaging your heart with God.
There is something in you that you need to discover.
Can I ask you one question?
How clearly do you see the world around you today?
When you look at your own life, what do you see?
When you look at your life, what do you see?
If you say you see setback, limitation, poverty, trouble, let me ask you the following question:
What does Jesus see when He is looking at you?
There is more to life than meets the ordinary eye -
there is man's point of view and we have eternity's perspective.
Which one is ruling your life today?
Look around you and you will see that many people are complaining, lamenting, crying,
weeping every day because their lives are centred, focused on what they are doing,
how they are feeling, how they are treated.
Worry destroys our sense of judgement; it makes the heart sick.
It affects your heart.
And the prophet says, our behavior is determined by the condition of our heart.
If you confess failure, you put failure on the throne.
Are you complaining about your life today?
if you do, it's because your heart is that way.
If you complain, it means your heart is that way.
With your complaints, you are constantly painting a public picture of your inner self -
the man himself, the real you.
But I have good news for you today.
When you realise that your heart is the fountain of all that you do,
then, you will see the need to allow Jesus to intervene on the inside of you.
Today, He wants to rebuild your life.
He wants to remove your tears.
He wants to show that there is something bigger than your problem.
Are you ready? Will you allow Him?
Change your focus.
Rebuilding you starts on the inside of you; it requires your attention.
By faith, listen to Jesus in the inner room.
By faith, listen to Him in the inner room telling you,
"Come to Me all you who are heavy laden and I will give you My rest".
When you step into the presence of Jesus, your thinking will change,
your attitude will change, everything about you will change.
You will no longer look at yourself in the natural; you will know what God says about you.
Are you ready?
Say, "Neighbour, keep focus.
Identify your source".
This leads me to our message today: FOCUS ON GOD.
Let someone say, "Focus on God".
Say, "Neighbour, focus on God".
Say to yourself, "My heart - focus on God".
Let me take you to the book of Hebrews 12. Let me start from verse 1.
"Therefore, since we are surrounded by so great a cloud of witnesses,
let us lay aside every weight, and the sin which so easily ensnares us,
and let us run with endurance the race that is set before us,
looking unto Jesus, the author and finisher of our faith,
who for the joy that was set before Him endured the cross,
despising the shame, and has sat down at the right hand of the throne of God."
Let someone say: A seat of power with power.
Focus on God.
You are what you give your attention to.
What you are looking at affects your thoughts.
A man's life is what his thoughts make it.
My life is what my thoughts make it.
Your behaviour and conduct cannot change until Jesus gives birth to a picture in you
of what He is looking at when He sees you.
When you focus on God today, you are indeed what God says you are
and you have what God says you have.
Daniel was a captive but he never referred to himself as a captive
because he steadfastly focused on his God and knew who he was.
That enabled him to have a mighty breakthrough and he became a biblical hero of faith.
Get connected.
No matter the trouble, get connected by faith.
When you discover what God has made you for, your life will change.
When you connect to God, when you focus on God,
then you will realise what God has made you for and how He cherishes your company.
Mankind is designed by God to think with God, plan with God, act with God and talk with God.
No state of being is as rewarding as living in tune with God.
Are you living in tune with God?
Are you planning with Him? Are you acting with Him?
Acting on the Word of God builds faith in the heart of the believer
because faith focuses on Jesus.
Faith focuses on Jesus.
Look to the cross.
By looking at God, looking unto God, meditating on God, faith comes spontaneously.
Jesus Christ possesses a nature that makes us to believe in Him.
He possesses a nature that makes it easy to believe and trust in Him.
When you realise how reliable the Lord is, faith comes naturally.
Faith comes naturally.
Say with a smile, "Faith comes naturally".
The transforming promise Jesus Christ offers you and I today is liberation.
With this liberation, you will no longer be ruled by your situation.
You will no longer be ruled by your senses.
He is here today to deliver you from it.
He is here to offer you the kind of liberation...
The Bible says, if the Son of God sets you free, you are free indeed.
I am free indeed.
I refuse to look at my problem - I focus on Him.
Once you focus on Him, your life will never remain the same again.
You will know what we call the 'dividend of democracy'.
The dividend of living in tune with God.
What is it?
Once you make Jesus Christ of Nazareth your CEO, your Director,
you become one directed by the Heavenly Father.
You become a man or woman wired, connected to the Heavenly Father.
Then, you will know that there is nobody and there will be nobody quite like you.
You are unique.
There is nobody, there will be nobody quite like me.
Stop comparing yourself with others.
Once you realise that, you will have a sensitivity you never had before.
You will know God as children know their father.
You will know God's opinion about yourself and others.
You will have a relationship with God Almighty.
And the man of God says: A sense of fatherhood will produce a natural basis for prayer.
And he said: "The greatest achievement on earth is to pray as God wants us to pray".
The greatest achievement on earth is to pray as God wants you to pray.
When you do, you will want what God wants
and you will want it for the reason God wants it.
Whatever you ask shall be provided.
One is rewarded when he prays, laughs, looks and smiles in faith.
The Spirit of Father dwelling in your heart will enable you to cry out, "Abba Father!" naturally.
He will allow you to pray naturally, speak naturally.
When you pray in love and faith, God prays.
When you talk in love and faith, God talks.
Let someone say: "The dividend of democracy".
Say, "Neighbour, focus on God".
If you focus on your problem, you lose focus on God.
Focus on God Almighty and not on the problem - no matter what comes, no matter what happens.
Look at what happened to the Israelites at the point of entering the promised land.
They focused on their giant.
Fear took hold of them
and fear increased the size of their giant, mentally.
They began to exalt their giant above God and they destroyed their confidence in God.
Whatever your situation is -
is it barrenness?
Is it poverty?
Is it family curse?
No matter what it is, focus on God.
Ask Hannah, she will tell you that a lack of absolute confidence in what they believe
is what causes people today to lose focus and balance
when the answer to their prayers seems to delay.
A lack of absolute trust in what they believe is what causes people to lose focus and balance
They begin to look for alternatives.
What kept Hannah from despairing was not what she saw but what she believed -
because she knew, she learnt the value of focusing on God.
The Scripture says that she was faced with
a seemingly overwhelming natural circumstance of barrenness for so many years
but she refused to give up to that voice of discouragement that was howling over her mind
because she was conscious of her faith.
She focused on God Almighty.
As you are sitting down, whatever giant that is troubling your heart -
Jesus is greater than all.
She ran to God's presence in prayer.
Prayer is not saying words.
She ran into God's presence and she prayed.
She was silent but her faith was not silent.
She poured out her heart before God
and the Bible says her heart was deeply engaged with God Almighty.
Immediately she heard the Word of faith, she believed
and the state of her mind was renewed instantly.
God's Word refreshes my mind; God's Spirit renews my strength.
Engage your heart as you are sitting down.
He is in our midst.
God Almighty is in the house through His Word, by His Spirit.
Jesus Christ listens to us when we pray
and He replies according to the state of our mind.
What is the state of your mind?
What is going through you right now?
She believed the Word and the Bible says,
immediately, she looked beyond her circumstance.
She looked beyond the state of barrenness and saw herself in a future state of fruitfulness.
as if it was already there, as if it was already true.
Her behaviour changed.
Say, "Neighbour, prayer changes me; faith causes things to happen".
It will happen for you today.
SCOAN Sunday Service
A humble believing soul that truly loves Jesus Christ
takes everything Jesus says and does it in good faith
and puts the best construction on it.
When she heard and she believed, her behaviour changed.
Immediately, she removed the garment of sorrow and a smile enlightened her face
because she believed that her request for a child was granted by God
and indeed, Samuel, the great prophet and judge was born.
What is your giant?
What is the problem that brought you here today?
As you are seated, check your heart.
Whatever you are experiencing now that is contrary to your heart's desire - stop!
Stop thinking about your problem.
Take time to change your focus because you are in His presence.
Say, "Neighbour, listen to my voice. If you run out of rope, grab onto faith".
Don't run from God; run to God
and that hope, that promise will become a reality.
Jesus said in John 8:12, "I am the light of the world.
He who follows Me will never walk in darkness but will have the light of life".
The only way you can see life clearly is to focus on Jesus.
It is not your mere wishful thinking but your rightful focus on Him
that determines who you are before God.
It is not your mere wishful thinking but your rightful focus
Focus on God, not on the problem.
Focus on Him.
What you regard as failure is not failure at all from eternity's perspective.
That problem, that trouble is not failure from eternity's perspective.
You need to know what God says about the situation.
You need to know what God says about you.
It is within you - it is hidden.
You need to discover it.
There is something in you that is dormant - as was my case.
Today is the day that the Lord has made.
I will rejoice and be glad in it.
If you believe, you will rejoice.
Focus on God Almighty, not on the trouble.
Your focus determines your response to the situation
and that response determines your future.
Look to God.
Discover it.
How do you discover it?
Meditation brings revelation.
As you are sitting down, that voice of condemnation, that voice of fear,
what people have been saying about you -
today, if you believe, you will get out of the wilderness.
Yielding your heart to the Word of God makes the Word of God a reality.
Yielding your heart to the Word of God makes the promise a reality
and when it does - the Bible says, you become Word-minded and God-minded.
When you are God-minded, you will know the mind of God about you and your situation.
The illumination of the Spirit of God will settle in your heart the truth from eternity's perspective.
The illumination of the Spirit of God will settle in my heart today the truth from eternity's perspective.
Look to Jesus.
Focusing on Jesus Christ of Nazareth puts everything else in its proper perspective.
Focusing on Him will put everything else in its proper perspective.
Are you barren?
Ask Hannah - you will see fruitfulness instead of barrenness.
You will see healing instead of sickness.
Are you poor?
Ask Jabez - you will see prosperity instead of setback.
Look to Jesus.
He has come to change your life.
He has changed my own; He will change your own if you believe.
King David, Daniel, Simon Peter, along with many heroes of faith -
they all struggled with various doubts in their lives
but they focused steadfastly on God Almighty and they prayed without ceasing.
They knew their enemy lost no time in plotting against them;
they lost no time in committing their lives to God Almighty.
The secret of a successful life is to learn to focus on God, not on the happenings around you.
Focus on Him.
No matter how unsteady your life appears to be, focus on God.
Engage your heart.
As you are sitting down, meditate on the Word of God and whatever you do will prosper.
Keep focus.
Tell your neighbour, "Keep focus; identify your Source".
Who is your Source?
Jesus Christ of Nazareth who raised the dead will change your life.
When you look at Him, you will see your life clearly.
May God Bless His Word.
TT: Juliet Kalenga Bwalya 25/12/2018
RV: Mel Flowers 26/12/2018